Because everyone loves an accurate period piece.
A Cock and Bull Story is a comedy, history film
directed by Michael Winterbottom.
Steve Coogan, an arrogant actor with low self-esteem and a complicated love life, is playing the eponymous role in an
adaptation of "The Life and Opinions of Tristram Shandy, Gentleman" being filmed at a stately home.
He constantly spars with actor Rob Brydon, who is playing Uncle Toby and
believes his role to be of equal importance to Coogan's.
Tristram Shandy / Walter Shandy / Steve Coogan, played by Steve Coogan.
Toby Shandy / Rob Brydon, played by Rob Brydon.
Elizabeth Shandy / Keeley Hawes, played by Keeley Hawes.
Susannah / Shirley Henderson, played by Shirley Henderson.
Trim, played by Raymond Waring.
Six-Year-Old Tristam, played by Conal Murphy.
A Cock and Bull Story (marketed in Australia, New Zealand and the United States as Tristram Shandy: A Cock and Bull
Story, and also credited as such) is a 2005 British comedy film directed by Michael Winterbottom.
It is a film-within-a-film, featuring Steve Coogan and Rob Brydon playing themselves as egotistical actors during the
making of a screen adaptation of Laurence Sterne's 18th-century metafictional novel Tristram Shandy.
Gillian Anderson and Keeley Hawes also play themselves in
addition to their Tristram Shandy roles.
Since the book is about a man attempting but failing to write his autobiography,
the film takes the form of being about failing to make the film.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, film in film, filmmaking.
The tone is lighthearted.